<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:py="http://genshi.edgewall.org/">
  <xi:include href="layout.xml"/>
  <head/>
  <body>
    <h2>Halp!</h2>
    <p>Welcome to the intelligent™ search engine for the Lojban dictionary!</p>
    <p>Using me is easy, just enter a search word up there! <sup>➚</sup></p>
    <p>There are however some neat tricks you might be interested in.</p>
    <h2>Restrict results by matching field</h2>
    <p>
      Prefix a query with the name of a field followed by a colon and that query will be limited to that field.
      This restricts the results of the rest of the query to entries that match that field-specific query.
    </p>
    <p>Example: <code><a href="${url_for('query', query='number type:cmavo')}">number type:cmavo</a></code>.</p>
    <p>
      The above gives you a list of all particles matching “number”.
      The fields you can search are: <em>word</em>, <em>gloss</em>,
      <em>affix</em>, <em>class</em>, <em>type</em>, <em>definition</em> and <em>notes</em>.
    </p>
    <h2>Wildcards</h2>
    <p>For the fields <em>affix</em>, <em>type</em> and <em>word</em>, some characters have special meanings.</p>
    <p>
      A <code>*</code> matches anything at that position, a <code>?</code> matches any single character.
      Also, <code>[abc]</code> matches any of “a”, “b” and “c” whereas <code>[!abc]</code> matches anything except those.
    </p>
    <p>Example: <code><a href="/${url_for('query', query='word:[bd]a?')}">word:[bd]a?</a></code>.</p>
    <p>This lists all words that begin with a “b” or a “d”, followed by an “a” and any other one character.</p>
    <h2>Other things to keep in mind</h2>
    <p>For text fields I compare the stem of words, so that “amused” finds “amusing” and “amusement”.</p>
    <p>Example: <code><a href="${url_for('query', query='amused')}">amused</a></code>.</p>
    <p>If you need a space in a query and don't mean two separate restrictions, you need to quote the query.</p>
    <p>Example: <code><a href="/${url_for('query', query='type:&quot;experimental gismu&quot;')}">type:"experimental gismu"</a></code>.</p>
    <p>
      I have an <a href="http://www.opensearch.org/">OpenSearch</a> description, which means you can add me as a search engine in Firefox.
      If you're using Chrome or Chromium I'm already set up for you, just type <code>vlasisku.lojban.org</code> followed by your search in the location bar.
      If you right click on the location bar you can edit search engines and set up a more convinient keyword for me.
    </p>
  </body>
</html>
